Doctor Who: Voyage of the Damned is a science fiction, tv
movie, mystery film directed by James Strong.
When disaster hits the Titanic, the Doctor uncovers
a threat to the whole human race.
Battling alongside aliens, saboteurs, robot Angels and a new friend
called Astrid, can he stop the Christmas inferno?
The Doctor, played by David Tennant.
Astrid Peth, played by Kylie Minogue.
Midshipman Alonso Frame, played by Russell Tovey.
Bannakaffalatta, played by Jimmy Vee.
Mr. Copper, played by Clive Swift.
Max Capricorn, played by George Costigan.
"Voyage of the Damned" is an episode of the British science
fiction television programme Doctor Who.
First broadcast on BBC One on 25 December 2007, it is the third Doctor
Who Christmas special since the show's revival in 2005.
The episode was written by Russell T Davies and directed by James Strong.
In the episode, the alien businessman Max Capricorn (George Costigan)
seeks revenge on his company after it votes him out.
He sets a starship replica of the Titanic on a collision course with Earth to
frame the board of directors for killing the humans on Earth.
The episode features the only performance in Doctor Who by the Australian singer
and actress Kylie Minogue, who plays the waitress Astrid Peth.
Davies described her casting as a "very exceptional case", having
written the part of Astrid specifically for Minogue.
She is a one-off companion of the Tenth Doctor who appears just in this episode.
Minogue's casting in the role was a major coup for Doctor Who, her
fame attracting much publicity for the episode.
Subsequently, much of the episode's success in terms of viewing
figures was attributed to Minogue's appearance in the role.
On its original airdate Christmas 2007, "Voyage of the Damned" was watched by 13.31 million viewers, the highest viewing figure for
Doctor Who since the 1979 serial City of Death and still the highest viewership of any episode since the show's revival.
It was the second most-watched programme of 2007, beaten only by the
episode of EastEnders which aired immediately after it.
Critical opinion about the episode was divided; the writing and
Minogue's performance were both praised and criticised.
The tone is intense and emotional and thought_provoking.